Guide to the Walter F. W. Lohnes Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Walter F. W. Lohnes papers
1960-1995
SC0322
Lohnes, Walter F.W.
80 Linear feet
Correspondence, reports, manuscripts, and budget papers, ca. 1960-1985; and records from the NDEA language institutes in Bad Boll, Germany, 1960-1969, including correspondence, schedules, memoranda, course materials, and reports. The latter materials are in English and German. Records pertaining to the Institute for Basic German including minutes, correspondence, reports, and course materials, 1976-1983; materials pertaining to the development of the GRE test in German, 1969-1975; records of the Academic Council at Stanford, 1967-1971; correspondence relating to overseas studies; and other academic records.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
Accession ARCH-1999-144 contains Lohnes personnel file and is restricted. This collection is otherwise open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Professor of German Studies at Stanford University.
Description of the Collection
Correspondence, reports, manuscripts, and budget papers, ca. 1960-1985; and records from the NDEA language institutes in Bad Boll, Germany, 1960-1969, including correspondence, schedules, memoranda, course materials, and reports. The latter materials are in English and German. Records pertaining to the Institute for Basic German including minutes, correspondence, reports, and course materials, 1976-1983; materials pertaining to the development of the GRE test in German, 1969-1975; records of the Academic Council at Stanford, 1967-1971; correspondence relating to overseas studies; and other academic records.
Access Terms
Lohnes, Walter F.W.; Stanford University. Academic Council.; Stanford University. Department of German Studies.; Stanford University. Institute for Basic German.; german language; German language--Study and teaching.; Graduate Record Examination.
Collection Contents
- Papers, Accession ARCH-1995-032
  - 1959-60 Material from different Institutes, Informative material (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1960 Academic: Notes on Institute (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1960 Academic: Calendar (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1960 Academic: Lectures (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1960 Academic: Tests (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1960 Academic: Books (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1960 Academic: Time Schedule (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1960 Academic: Letters to Participants (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Final Report on the National Defense Language Institute Conducted by Stanford University at Bad Boll, Germany June 20-August 20, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1960: Letters to participants (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 1960: Office of Education Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1960: Institutes Informative Material (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 1960/61 Correspondence w/ staff (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1960/61 General Correspondence and Information (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 1961 Bad Boll Office of Education: Financial Report (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 1961 Bad Boll Office of Education: Manuals (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 1961 Bad Boll Office of Education: Instructions (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - 1961 Bad Boll Office of Education: Contract (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 1961 Bad Boll Office of Education: Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 1961 Bad Boll Office of Education: New Plan of Operation (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 1961 Bad Boll Office of Education: Original Plan of Operation (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 1961 Bad Boll Office of Education: Original Proposal (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 1961 Bad Boll Office of Education: O.E. Information (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 1961 Boll Technical: Notes (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 1961 Boll Technical: Participant Finances (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 1961 Boll Technical: Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 1961 Boll Technical: Bonn: Regierung (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 1961 Boll Technical: Omnibus (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 1961 Boll Technical: Auto (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - 1961 Boll Technical: Budget (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - 1961 Boll Technical: Appointments (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - 1961 Boll Technical: Evang Akademie (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - 1961 Boll Technical: Jan. Trip (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - 1961 Boll Technical: Letters to Participants (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 1961 Boll Academic: Newsletter (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - 1961 Boll Academic: Berlin (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 1961 Boll Academic: Köln (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 1961 Boll Academic: Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - 1961 Boll Academic: Nürnberg (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 1961 Boll Academic: Frestspiele (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - 1961 Boll Academic: Schedules (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - 1961 Boll Academic: Area Studies (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - 1961 Boll Academic: Linguistics (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - 1961 Boll Academic: General (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - 1961 Boll Academic: MLA Tests (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - 1961 Boll Academic: Unknown (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - 1961 Boll Academic: Participants (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Brochure for 1961 Institute (Draft) (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - 1961 Miscellaneous: Schedules, Participant List, Printed Letters, Etc. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - 1961: Final Report on the National Defense Language Institute Conducted by Stanford University at Bad Boll, Germany June 19-August 19, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - 1961: Final Report on the National Defense Language Institute Conducted at Southern Illinois University, Carbondale, Illinois June 26, 1961-August 11, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - 1961: Final Report: National Defense Education Act Summer Institute, 1961, for Teachers of Elementary and Secondary School German @ University of Washington, Seattle (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - 1961: Germany As We Saw It; a report presented by the participants in the 1961 Stanford NDEA Institute held at Bad Boll, Germany, August 18, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - 1962 Boll Technical: Notes (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - 1962 Boll Technical: Letters to Participants (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - 1962 Boll Technical: Plane (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - 1962 Boll Technical: Participant Finances (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - 1962 Boll Technical: Participants (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - 1962 Boll Technical: Goethe Institut (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - 1962 Boll Technical: Evang. Akademie (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - 1962 Boll Technical: Budget (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - 1962 Boll Technical: Auto (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - 1962 Boll Technical: Misc. (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - 1962 Boll Technical: Staff Contracts and Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - 1962 Boll Technical: Bonn-Regierung (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - 1962 Boll Academic: Omnibus (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - 1962 Boll Academic: Nürnberg (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - 1962 Boll Academic: München (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - 1962 Boll Academic: Köln (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - 1962 Boll Academic: Berlin (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - 1962 Boll Academic: Fetspiele (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - 1962 Boll Academic: Materials (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - 1962 Boll Academic: Tests (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - 1962 Boll Academic: Schedules (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - 1962 Boll Academic: Area Studies (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - 1962 Boll Office of Education: Newsletter & Pamphlet (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - 1962 Boll Office of Education: Contract (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - 1962 Boll Office of Education: Correspondence O.E (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - 1962 Boll Office of Education: Instructions (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - 1962 Boll Office of Education: Manuals (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - 1962 Boll Office of Education: O.E. Information (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - 1962 Boll Office of Education: Original Proposal (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - 1962 Boll Office of Education: Inst. International Education (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Final Report National Defense Education Act Summer Institute, 1962 For Teachers of Secondary School German University of Washington, Seattle (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Final Report on the National Defense Language Institute Conducted by Stanford university @ Bad Boll Germany June 17- August 18, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Germany As We Saw It; Second Edition, 1962 (A report presented by the participants in the 1962 NDEA Advanced German Institute held by Stanford University at Bad Boll, Germany. August 18, 1962) (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 1963 Boll Technical: Misc. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 1963 Boll Technical: Participants (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 1963 Boll Technical: Letters to Participants (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - 1963 Boll Technical: Participant Finances (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - 1963 Boll Technical: Units--Correspondence w/ Registrar (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - 1963 Boll Technical: General (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - 1963 Boll Technical: Finances (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - 1963 Boll Technical: Staff Contracts & Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - 1963 Boll Technical: Ev. Akademie, Boll Korresp Fischer, Boll (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - 1963 Boll Technical: Bonn--Regierang (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - 1963 Boll Technical: Misc. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - 1963 Boll 3rd Level: Misc. Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - 1963 Boll 3rd Level: Bonn (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - 1963 Boll 3rd Level: Participants (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - 1963 Boll 3rd Level: Correspondence Klaiber-Wurz (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - 1963 Boll 3rd Level: Field Trip Hotels (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - 1963 Boll 3rd Level: Schwabisch Hall (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - 1963 Boll 3rd Level: Strasbourg Wurzburg (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - 1963 Boll 3rd Level: Wednesday Trips (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - 1963 Boll 3rd Level: Bus Transportation (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - 1963 Boll 3rd Level: Schedules (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - 1963 Boll 3rd Level: Course Description--Units (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - 1963 Projected 3rd Level: Itinerary (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - 1963 Projected 3rd Level: Units (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - 1963 Projected 3rd Level: Participants (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - 1963 Projected 3rd Level: Area Studies (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - 1963 Projected 3rd Level: Schedules (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - 1963 Projected 3rd Level: Field Trip (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - 1963 Boll Trips/ Academic: Airplane (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - 1963 Boll Trips/ Academic: Omnibus (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - 1963 Boll Trips/ Academic: Berlin (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - 1963 Boll Trips/ Academic: Nuremberg (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - 1963 Boll Trips/ Academic: Munchen (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - 1963 Boll Trips/ Academic: Koln (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - 1963 Boll Trips/ Academic: Fetspiele (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - 1963 Boll Trips/ Academic: Materials (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - 1963 Boll Trips/ Academic: Schedules (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - 1963 Boll Trips/ Academic: Area Studies (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - 1963 Boll Trips/ Academic: Tests (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - 1963 Boll Office of Education: Contract (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - 1963 Boll Office of Education: Correspondence-O.E. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - 1963 Boll Office of Education: Inspector (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - 1963 Boll Office of Education: Corres. W/ Inst. Director (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - 1963 Boll Office of Education: NE4-1963 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - 1963 Boll Office of Education: O.E. Information (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - 1963 Boll Office of Education: Financial Report (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - 1963 Boll Office of Education: Instructions (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - 1963 Boll Office of Education: Manuals (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - 1963 Boll Office of Education: Original Proposal (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Bound Publication: Final Report on the National Defense Language Institute conducted by Stanford University at Bad Boll, Germany June 17-August 21, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Germany As We Saw It; Third Edition, 1963 (A report presented by the participants in the 1963 NDEA Advanced German Institute held by Stanford University at Bad Boll, Germany. August 15, 1963) (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Germany in Europe 1963 (A report presented by the participants in the 1963 Third-Level NDEA Institute conducted by Stanford University in Bad Boll, Germany. August 21, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - 1964 Boll Participants & Staff: Participants (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - 1964 Boll Participants & Staff: Letters to Participants (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - 1964 Boll Participants & Staff: Participant Finances (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - 1964 Boll Participants & Staff: Credit/Registrar (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - 1964 Boll Participants & Staff: Staff, Contracts, Correspondence (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - 1964 Boll Participants & Staff: Boll Evang. Akademie (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - 1964 Boll Participants & Staff: Bonn (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - 1964 Boll Participants & Staff: Misc. (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - 1964 Boll Trips & Schedules: Corres. W/ Stanford (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - 1964 Boll Trips & Schedules: Airplane (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - 1964 Boll Trips & Schedules: Bus/Car (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - 1964 Boll Trips & Schedules: Berlin (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - 1964 Boll Trips & Schedules: Nuremberg (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - 1964 Boll Trips & Schedules: Munich (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - 1964 Boll Trips & Schedules: Cologne (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - 1964 Boll Trips & Schedules: Festivals, Concerts (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - 1964 Boll Trips & Schedules: Schedules (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - 1964 Boll Trips & Schedules: Area Studies (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - 1964 Boll Trips & Schedules: Materials (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - 1964 Boll Trips & Schedules: Tests (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - 1964 Boll Trips & Schedules: Linguistic Methods (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - 1964 Boll Office of Education: Instructions (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - 1964 Boll Office of Education: Manuals (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - 1964 Boll Office of Education: Correspondence O.E. (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - 1964 Boll Office of Education: O.E. Information (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - 1964 Boll Office of Education: Correspondence w/ other Institute Directors (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - 1964 Boll Office of Education: Contract (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - 1964 Boll Office of Education: Proposal/Plan of Operation (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - 1964 Boll Office of Education: Financial Corres w/ Stanford (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Final Report NDEA Summer Institute in German Montana State College Bozeman, Montana 1964 (Report of the Director on The National Defense Language Institute for Secondary School Teachers of German) (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Final Report on the National Defense Language Institute Conducted at University of Washington June 19-August 13, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Final Report on the National Defense Language Institute conducted at Albright College reading, Pennsylvania June 14, 1964 to July 31, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Institut de Langue Français NDEA A Femmes Sous Les Auspices Du College Ste Catherine Et Du United States Office of Education, Travauz Pratiques De Civilisation, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - 1964 Profiles on Five German Towns: A report presented by the participants in the 1964 NDEA Advanced German Institute held by Stanford University @ Bad Boll Germany August 22, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Final Report on the National Defense Language Institute conducted by Stanford University at Bad Boll, Germany June 18-August 22, 1964 (Photographs tucked inside) (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - 1965 Boll Participants & Staff: Participants (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - 1965 Boll Participants & Staff: Letters to Participants (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - 1965 Boll Participants & Staff: Participants' Finances (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - 1965 Boll Participants & Staff: Credit (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - 1965 Boll Participants & Staff: Staff--Contracts (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - 1965 Boll Participants & Staff: Correspondence w. Frau Klaiber (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - 1965 Boll Participants & Staff: Evang. Akademie Boll (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - 1965 Boll Participants & Staff: Bonn (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - 1965 Boll Participants & Staff: Misc. (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - 1965 Boll Office of Education: Financial Corresp. W/ Stanford (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - 1965 Boll Office of Education: O.E. Instructions (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - 1965 Boll Office of Education: Manuals (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - 1965 Boll Office of Education: Correspondence w/ Office of Education (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - 1965 Boll Office of Education: Corresp w/ other Institutions (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - 1965 Boll Office of Education: Contract (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - 1965 Boll Office of Education: Plan of Operation (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Final Report on the NDEA Institute for Elementary and Secondary School Teachers of German held by Stanford University @ Bad Boll Germany June 17-August 20, 1965 submitted by: Walter F.W. Lohnes Assc. Prof of German Stanford U. (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - 1965 Profiles on Five German Towns: A report presented by the participants in the 1965 NDEA Advanced German Institute held by Stanford University @ Bad Boll Germany August 20, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - 1966 Boll Trips: Plane-Bus-Car (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - 1966 Boll Trips: Berlin (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - 1966 Boll Trips: Cologne (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - 1966 Boll Trips: Materials (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - 1966 Boll Trips: Area Studies (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - 1966 Boll Trips: Tests (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - 1966 Boll Trips: Concerts Etc. (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - 1966 Boll Participants & Staff: Schedules (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - 1966 Boll Participants & Staff: Participants (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - 1966 Boll Participants & Staff: Letters to Participants (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - 1966 Boll Participants & Staff: Credit (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - 1966 Boll Participants & Staff: Staff-Contracts (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - 1966 Boll Participants & Staff: Boll-Akademie (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - 1966 Boll Participants & Staff: Bonn (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - 1966 Boll Participants & Staff: Misc. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - 1966 Boll Office of Education: Financial Stanford (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - 1966 Boll Office of Education: O.E. Instructions (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - 1966 Boll Office of Education: Manuals (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - 1966 Boll Office of Education: O.E. Correspondence (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - 1966 Boll Office of Education: Plan of Operation (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - 1966 Boll Office of Education: Contract (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - 1966 Boll Office of Education: Institute Correspondence (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - 1966 Project 15 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - 1966 Project 15 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - 1966 Profiles on Five German Towns: A report presented by the participants in the 1966 NDEA Advanced German Institute held by Stanford University @ Bad Boll Germany August 19, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - 1966 Final Technical Report on the NDEA Institute for Advanced study for Elementary and Secondary School Teachers in German held by Stanford @ Bad Boll June 18- August 19, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - 1967 Boll Participants & Staff: Schedules (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - 1967 Boll Participants & Staff: Participants (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - 1967 Boll Participants & Staff: Letters to Participants (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - 1967 Boll Participants & Staff: Credit (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - 1967 Boll Participants & Staff: Staff-Contracts (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - 1967 Boll Participants & Staff: Coop. Institutions (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - 1967 Boll Participants & Staff: Boll Akademie (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - 1967 Boll Participants & Staff: Bonn (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - 1967 Boll Participants & Staff: Misc. (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Final Technical Report on the NDEA Institute for Advanced Study for Teachers and Prospective Teachers of German in Grades 7-12 Held by Stanford U. in Berlin and Bad Boll, Germany October 9, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - 1968 Boll Application Requests: A (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - 1968 Boll Application Requests: B (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - 1968 Boll Application Requests: C (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - 1968 Boll Application Requests: D (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - 1968 Boll Application Requests: E (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - 1968 Boll Application Requests: F (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - 1968 Boll Application Requests: G (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - 1968 Boll Application Requests: H (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - 1968 Boll Application Requests: I (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - 1968 Boll Application Requests: J (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - 1968 Boll Application Requests: K (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - 1968 Boll Application Requests: L (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - 1968 Boll Application Requests: Mc (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - 1968 Boll Application Requests: M (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - 1968 Boll Application Requests: N (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - 1968 Boll Application Requests: O (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - 1968 Boll Application Requests: P (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - 1968 Boll Application Requests: R (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - 1968 Boll Application Requests: S (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - 1968 Boll Application Requests: T (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - 1968 Boll Application Requests: U (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - 1968 Boll Application Requests: V (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - 1968 Boll Application Requests: W (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - 1968 Boll Application Requests: Y (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - 1968 Boll Application Requests: Z (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - 1968 Letters to Boll Applicants: Ineligible (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - 1968 Letters to Boll Applicants: Eligible (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - 1968 Boll Office of Education: O.E. Instructions (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - 1968 Boll Office of Education: O.E. Correspondence (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - 1968 Boll Office of Education: Plan of Operation (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - 1968 Boll Office of Education: Contract (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - 1968 Boll Office of Education: Budget/Proposal (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - 1968 Boll Office of Education: Measure Research Center, Iowa (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - 1968 Boll Office of Education: Correspondence w/ other Institutes (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - 1968 NDEA Final Grades and Course Descriptions (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - 1969 Bad Boll: Budget (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - 1969 Bad Boll: Berlin (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - 1969 Bad Boll: Akademie (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - 1969 Bad Boll: Office of Education (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - 1969 Bad Boll: Staff (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - 1969 Bad Boll: Cooperating Institutes (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - 1969 Bad Boll: Bank (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - 1969 Bad Boll: Participants' Mail (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - 1969 Bad Boll: Participants List (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - 1969 Bad Boll: Book Orders (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - 1969 Bad Boll: Busses & Calendars (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - 1969 Bad Boll: Planes (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - 1969 Bad Boll: Misc. (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - EPDA Institute for Advanced Study in Berlin and Bad Boll, Germany June 21-August 22, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 30)
- Papers, Accession ARCH-1996-011
  - Assorted correspondence, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Educational Testing Service (ETS) - language tests, 1968-69 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1972-73 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence from Stanford-in-Austria, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1971-72 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Material for faculty meeting, autumn quarter, 1970-71 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence and tests, 1973-74 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence and lists of graduate students, 1986-87 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - International Studies Comm'n, 1985-86 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Tiro Project, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence with library (CDP) - Stanford Collection of German, Austrian, and Swiss Culture, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Undergraduate majors - graduated, 1989-1993 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Undergraduate major advising, 1989-1995 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence from Stanford-in-Germany, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Courses and degrees (C&D), 1971-72 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Dean's Advisory Committee on Modern Foreign Languages - correspondence, 1978-1985 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Staff schedules - individual, 1969-70 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Staff time schedules, 1968-69 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Memos - lower div., 1968-69 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Darwin, Kathleen (Ph.D. file), 1972 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence from Beutelsbach (Stanford-in-Germany), 1973 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence from Beutelsbach (Stanford-in-Germany), 1973 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Educational Testing Service (ETS) - undergraduate exam, 1968-69 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1981-82 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Department correspondence, 1986-87 (Box 4, Folder 2)